Kurozu-cho , town of my birth . Let me tell you the story ...
of a strangeness that happened here .
U * ZU * MA * KI [ spiral ]
Oh no ... I 'll lose again .
Chapter 1 : Premonition
Yamaguchi !
Surprised ?
Right ?
Of course !
It 's just something I do .
It is , huh ? How nice for you .
Wh-What do you want ?
Goshima ... be my girlfriend .
What ? !
Ok , ok ...
You win , I 'm surprised . But I 'm in a hurry . Bye .
Goshima ! I 'm serious ! I really like you !
Is that Shuichi 's dad ?
Hello .
You 're here .
Guess I win today .
Hey !
Two on a bike 's illegal , you dumb kids .
Wanted : Junji Ito
Beauty Salon " Marble "
Hello !
Back from school ?
It 's all tidied up inside .
Thanks so much .
Huh ?
The sign 's gone .
Oh , dear ... You 're right !
I don 't get why we need tests .
It 's okay for someone smart like you , Shuichi ...
Me , I could keep up in middle school pretty easy ...
Not now in high school , though .
Especially math . I can 't get it .
Makes me dizzy .
So ...
Yeah ? ... What .
I saw your dad on the street a while ago .
He was filming this snail shell ...
But ... maybe ... it wasn 't him .
It was dark .
It was him .
He 's weird lately .
Is he ?
Kinda , yeah .
You don 't look well these days either ...
Too much studying , maybe ?
I think you can relax a bit ...
You 'll get into a good university . Your grades are great , and -
... Kirie .
Will you elope with me ?
What ? Elope ?
No , you can 't , can you .
Right out of the blue ? There 's a time for everything ...
Sorry . Forget I said it .
Let 's go .
Shuichi ...
480 yen , please .
Here you go .
200,000 yen change .
That 's right , I hear your father took top prize .
Yes , he did .
That 's great .
So now he 's " Goshima-sensei , " eh ?
No , please don 't call him that .
Oh , right .
It 's still a special day , so ...
Are you sure ?
Of course ! To celebrate .
Oh , wow ... Thanks !
You get better and better , Mr. Goshima .
You won the Midoriyama Exhibition prize , didn 't you ?
Oh , that ? ... that was just luck .
No , no ...
Pottery is the truest of the arts .
The one with the true uzumaki .
The uzumaki as art ? I see .
I do see ... !
Uzumaki ! Sometimes it makes me dizzy , I must admit .
Marvelous .
Well , Mr. Goshima ? Will you create me a piece ?
A platter that will really make my eyes spin .
Make me one in an uzumaki pattern .
So , a platter with an uzumaki pattern .
Yes .
A spiral .
One that goes round and round and round .
Round and round and round .
Yes .
All right .
I 'll do it .
Excellent .
You know , Mr. Goshima ...
when I see the uzumaki I feel ...
a sense ...
of deepest mystery .
You feel deepest mystery .
I knew you 'd understand , Mr. Goshima .
The uzumaki is sublime .
It is , in itself , the greatest work of art .
And you are the great artist ...
bringing it forth !
Yum .
And here 's dessert .
Fancy today , aren 't we .
It 's from the greengrocer , to celebrate .
Well , then !
Another blessing from your o-mamori charm , Kirie .
Take some credit , Dad .
Shuichi 's father even said so . Gotta keep it up , now .
Guess so .
Here goes ...
Hey-y-y , how 'd you know ? Were you listening ?
Oh , that 's a good melon .
Is it ?
You 're right ! That is good .
Isn 't it ?
Delicious .
Kirie
I was such a klutz , but you were always there .
Even when my mother died ...
Don 't cry , Kirie .
Don 't cry .
I 'll be your mother for you .
I don 't want a boy for a mother !
... Kirie . Will you elope with me ?
Elope , huh ?
Not quite yet ...
dear Shuichi .
Morning .
Shuichi 's trying for a Tokyo university , isn 't he .
And what 's it to you ... ?
I guess so , yeah .
You " guess " ? You mean you haven 't talked about it ?
What kind 've answer 's that ? ! You 're going out , aren 't you ?
We 're not " going out , " exactly .
Now see ? That 's where you -
Surprised ?
Yamaguchi !
You 're wasting your time .
Kirie has a boyfriend .
Shiho !
I know . Saito Shuichi . Forget him , he 's a drag .
If I can score a hottie like you , I 'll make everyone jealous .
You 're the drag . Come on , Kirie .
Hey , wait !
Don 't follow us !
Goshima !
That 's some stalker you got .
He ambushed me yesterday , too .
He what ? !
Better be careful . You 're not the first one he 's bothered .
For real ?
When you see him ...
do this .
What 's that .
" Skirt " around him .
Three points .
Three-and-a-half .
Three .
Miyazaki !
I liked him , too ...
You all right , Kirie ?
Yeah . Thanks .
I 'm fine now .
What a nasty thing to see .
They said he was doing acrobatics on the handrail .
What an idiot .
But didn 't he look like he had a smile on his face ?
Would you smile ?
He died happy .
Sekino ...
It doesn 't matter how , so long as you 're noticed , yes ?
If you 're not noticed , it 's like you 're not alive .
I love it when people look at me .
Wouldn 't you two agree ?
I don 't really like sticking out ...
The guy 's dead , okay ? !
' Cause it 's the only way he 'd be noticed .
I , too , want to be noticed ... especially now .
I want to be seen ... in the truest possible way .
It was a spiral staircase , wasn 't it .
How 'd you know ?
The uzumaki .
The " uzuma " what ?
What 's the uzumaki .
The spiral-pattern draws the eye .
Whoever drew it , wanted to draw other eyes , too .
The uzumaki drew the dead guy into it .
No way .
It was just an accident .
I 've started having a bad feeling about this place ...
I get dizzy just coming home through that tunnel .
This town 's cursed by the uzumaki .
I don 't feel anything ...
My dad went to your place yesterday , didn 't he ?
Huh ? Yeah ...
He wanted a dish with an uzumaki pattern .
He called my dad a great artist - -
... You see ? Uzumaki .
But that 's silly . Lots of people like uzumaki patt - -
You don 't know what you 're talking about !
I 'm sorry .
My dad 's over the edge .
He 's stopped going to work . He just walks around ...
bringing home anything he finds with uzumaki .
The house is full of stuff . If you call , he won 't answer .
He just sits there , staring .
Just last night ...
Dad 's sick , you know .
And you can 't take much more .
He needs help .
Beauty Salon " Marble "
Here .
It 's been a long day .
Hey ...
More spiral fishcake .
That was the last of it .
What ? No more ?
I 'm sorry .
Don 't apologize .
And I 'm supposed to eat miso soup without it ? !
That calmed him down a bit .
It 's not funny .
But ...
Come to my house .
You 'll see .
Dumb kids !
You 've no idea what you 've done . I can 't allow it .
Please , stop ...
Dad ! What 's wrong with you ? !
My collection ... she threw it out !
I threw it out .
You 're better off without it .
What ? !
What would you know ? !
You weren 't always like this ...
If only you could see - -
Ah , well .
If it 's gone , it 's gone .
The collection 's not important . The idea 's enough .
Finally , I 've realized that .
One makes one 's own uzumaki .
You listen , and listen good :
One brings forth one 's own uzumaki .
Like this , for example .
Chapter 2 : Erosion
What 's wrong ? You seem down .
Haven 't seen Shuichi , huh ?
Did you fight ?
Another girl ?
You got dumped ?
Then what 's wrong ? !
Ishikawa !
Yes , sir ...
Do you want to fail again ?
Katayama ! What time do you think it is ? !
S-Sorry ...
I-I don 't know what ... I left at the usual time , but -
I know .
It 's ' cause he 's so slow . A snail goes faster .
Tsumura ...
" Snail , snail ; you leave a trail ... "
Oyama !
Shut up with that stupid song !
Katayama ...
It 's true you only come to school these days when it rains .
You come to the office later .
Y-Yessir .
Yeah , in two years .
We 'll be graduated then .
Just sit down , will you ?
I hate to agree with Tsuyama , but he really is slow , isn 't he .
Ishikawa !
Yes , sir .
I didn 't say you could sit down .
You slimy fuck ...
I can 't even look at you , fat boy .
You 're pissin ' me off .
Like I wanna hurl .
Hey .
Hey !
Hey ! Cut that out !
Oyama ! Stop it !
Tsumura !
All of you ! Sit down !
Don 't worry . We 'll find someone .
Surprised ?
Move .
Open it .
Don 't want to .
Won 't you even look inside ? You can at least open it .
Did you like that ?
Go away !
Why don 't you like me ? !
You 're just not my type . Now leave me alone .
Goshima ... I won 't give up , you know .
I 'll make you like me .
I 'm home . Sorry it 's late .
Welcome back .
I 'll get supper .
Kirie ...
Would you mind bringing this dish over to Shuichi 's father ?
Wha-a-t ?
What , " wha-a-t . "
if he doesn 't like it , tell him I 'll do another .
Hello ?
Shuichi ... ?
Hey !
Shuichi , you there ?
Shuichi ?
Shuichi ... ?
Hey , I said .
Where are you ?
Shuichi ?
Shuichi ... ?
That 's Kirie !
Kirie .
What 's wrong ?
Kirie , what 's the matter ?
Uzumaki .
Did you hear how he died ?
Heart attack , wasn 't it ?
No , suicide ... !
Though they haven 't said that to the relatives .
Come to think of it , the coffin was closed .
Wonder what he looked like ... ?
I 'm counting on you .
Are you okay ? You look pale .
What about you ?
I had a feeling something like this would happen .
It 's my mother who worries me .
I haven 't told her yet , but when this is over ...
Mrs. Saito ! What 's wrong ?
What 's that ?
No more ! Please ! Stop it !
Mom ! What 's wrong ?
Shuichi !
Mom ! Calm down !
Shuichi ... There , up there ! It 's your father !
Mom ! Mom !
Call an ambulance !
Mom !
Dragonfly Pond ...
Be brave .
Kirie ...
Let 's get out of this town before it 's too late .
What ?
I told you ...
This town 's cursed by the uzumaki .
We 've got to get out .
What about your mother ? She 'll need a few more days .
Are you Saito Shuichi ?
Tamura Ichiro , Reporter
My sympathies .
You knew my father ?
Actually , a few weeks ago he came to our office .
He said he was interested in town history .
We showed him what we had .
Was he acting strange ?
May I ?
Well ...
He kept going on about uzumaki .
The police told me how your father died .
What I want to know is , why did he die like that ?
It 's not for an article .
I just want to know why .
I keep thinking his death has some deeper significance .
Plus there was that smoke at the crematorium ...
Will you trust me ?
Hello . ... ?
Hey , isn 't that - - ?
My dad taped it .
He was taping when he died , too .
Hello ... ?
Let 's see it again .
A mirror ?
My mom 's mirror .
But why take in a mirror ?
Not to mention - -
Can I hang onto the video ? I 'll call soon as I find something .
So you and Shuichi spend a lot of time together ?
Yes ... We 've been friends since we were little .
Ah , childhood friends , eh ?
The best kind to be .
It 's just ...
He 's always been there for me .
He 's always cheered me up when I 've been down .
Now , though ...
Now it 's he who needs me .
I 've no idea what to do .
What is there to do ...
for poor Shuichi ?
There 's nothing .
At a time like this , there 's nothing anyone can do .
He 'll have to find his own way through .
Still ... Call it reporter 's instinct ...
but I have the feeling just having you around 's a big comfort to him .
" Comfort " ... ?
Sure .
So be confident , and do your best .
You 've gotta be strong .
... OK .
I 'll need directions to your house .
Right at the next corner .
Next corner , turn right .
What th - - ! ?
Dad !
You all right ?
I 'm fine .
But you 're covered in mud !
I went for clay at Dragonfly Pond .
Dad ...
Dad !
You 'll catch cold .
Go away ! Go back to bed .
But ...
Get your ass back in bed !
Next .
You study for the biology test , Kirie ?
What ?
You didn 't forget ?
You 're the girl from another planet lately . You really OK ?
Whoa , whoa , whoa ... Check that .
Was her hair like that earlier ? I don 't remember .
Dude , yo , slow down . Or you 're gonna puke it up later .
Mirror
Serpent
Kagami , " mirror . " Kagami , " serpent . " Same reading , different characters .
Mirror
Serpent
Worship the Serpent
Serpent Cult
Eternal Life
" Ancient Mirrors Retrieved from Dragonfly Pond "
For your mom . She likes sweet things , right ?
Thanks .
Oh , sorry . It 's just my mom can 't have those .
Sorry .
The greatest work of art . She sees my dad there , dead .
I 'm so sorry ...
Fingerprints are uzumaki too , so we musn 't let her see hands .
Sorry about the weird outfits .
Sorry about the weird outfits , but the staff 's being careful , too .
She 's obliterated every uzumaki she can find .
" Obliterated " ... How ?
You 'll see .
Her " spirophobia " is the first thing we have to work on .
Saito Yukie
Mom .
Why , Kirie ... !
Saito Shuichi , Saito Shuichi ...
Please come to the nurses ' station .
I 'm Saito . Someone paged me ?
Yes , a Mr. Tamura wants you to call him right away .
All right , thank you .
Hello ? It 's Saito ...
Shuichi ?
I 've found something important .
Can you meet me at Dragonfly Pond fight away ?
Right now ?
Yes , all right .
Here 's another one .
What are you doing ? !
If my mom realizes there 's uzumaki in the ear , who knows what she ... ?
Mr. Tamura seems to have found something .
We may solve the mystery yet .
So you shut me down for a loser like this ... ?
Kirie , who is he .
It 's OK , though .
I 've made up my mind .
We 're in a hurry -
Shut up !
Goshima , I guarantee that you will never , ever forget me .
Yamaguchi !
Kirie ...
We used to play here .
You were such a scaredy-cat .
Once I said there was a big snake here who ate little girls ...
and you burst out crying .
I remember .
It made you uncomfortable .
You told me not to worry , ' cause you 'd always protect me .
It 's so quiet ...
It 's as if none of it were real .
But if this is all a dream , I hope I wake up soon .
It 's not a dream . Real people are really dying .
This town is cursed by the uzumaki .
Kirie ?
Shuichi ...
I 'm scared ...
I 'll protect you ...
Shuichi ...
Chapter 3 : Visitation
Saito Yukie
Yukie ...
Why do you hate the spiral so ?
All this time , it 's been inside you ...
I want to go deep inside your ear ...
Let me curl aground it and sleep inside you ...
Stop it !
The spiral is deep inside you ...
deep inside your ear ...
The spiral is in your ear ...
The spiral ...
No ! There 's that smoke again ...
It spirals like that when they cremate someone ...
whether they 're from this town or not .
Say ...
Doesn 't that look like a face ... ?
Eww ! You 're right !
You see it , right ?
Mom
Now for weather .
Unsettled weather conditions this season ...
have , thus far , prevented typhoon formation .
Finally , the first typhoon of the year has appeared .
It 's about to make landfall .
Strangeness in Kurozu-cho ! ?
Hello . I 'm Maruyama Chie .
As a large typhoon nears Kurozu-cho ...
a bizarre series of incidents has taken place .
First , giant snails have appeared ...
reportedly as large as a human being .
Giant Snails Invade Local High School !
Hang on , wait a sec ...
They-y-y 're so cu-u-ute ...
There 's this guy ? In our class ? Called [ BLEEP ] ?
So he gets this uzumaki ? On his back ?
And he only comes to school on rainy days , right ?
It 's like this totally cute pattern , though .
Just thinking about it , I ... Oh my god !
That asshole ? Yeah , that 's [ BLEEP ] . He starts chugging tons of water ...
then he starts gettin ' real slow .
My dad , he says he saw these " human snails " outside town .
These huge snails were , apparently , once human .
Although the creatures ' whereabouts are currently unknown ...
these two so-called human snails were last seen leaving town ...
for the hills outside it , where a search is now underway .
But the strange events in Kurozu-cho don 't end there ... !
In common : a strange spiral pattern that -
This town 's doomed . We gotta get out of here .
I 'll get my father .
Kirie ...
I 'll come with you .
How much further ?
How much further ? The tunnel .
Good . Here 's hoping the next story won 't be so weird .
I can 't see the other end ...
" I-I-I found a sp-i-i-ral ... "
Huh ?
He was right here ...
Maybe he 's at the kiln .
Dad ?
Where can he be ?
Dad ...
Shuichi ! What 's wrong ?
Kirie ...
It 's got me .
Stay back !
Get away from here . It 's too late for me now .
No !
No .
You said we 'd both go .
Kirie ...
I 'm sorry .
I ... I didn 't protect you ...
You can do it , we ...
Kirie ... I ...
Shuichi ?
Shuichi ... ?
No !
You promised me !
You said that you 'd always ...
be here to care for me .
Don 't die on me !
Don 't die .
Come into the spiral ...
Come into the uzumaki .
Kirie ...
Kurozu-cho , town of my birth . Let me tell you the story ...
Kirie Goshima ERIKO HATSUNE
Shuichi Saito FAN FHI
Kyoko Sekino HINAKOI SAEKI
Chie Maruyama EUN-KYUNG SHIN
Yukie Saito KEIKO TAKAHASHI
Toshio Saito REN OSUGI
Executive Producers TOYOYUKI YOKOHAMA
Producer MIYAKE SUMIJI
Based on the Manga " Uzumaki " by JUNJI ITO
Screenplay TAKAO NITTA
Director of Photography GEN KOBAYASHI
Art Director HIROSHI HAYASHIDA
Music TETSURO KASHIBUCHI
Planning DAI MIYAZAKI
Directed by HIGUCHINSKY